Buongiorno. Let me continue in English,
but this session is for Italian
customers and partners because we will
we will be talking about very Italy
specific
process.
Because Italian localization for a long
time had advanced subcontracting
capabilities already handling transfer
of uh
raw materials
between company and subcontractor, work
in progress items, and managing prices.
With
new subcontracting app available
globally
and in Italy, we are
discontinuing the existing Italian
functionality and replacing it with a
subcontracting app. And here we will be
talking about migration path or how to
transfer from the legacy subcontracting
to new app.
Conceptually,
new subcontracting app includes a lot of
features which available in Italy and
more.
There is one significant difference in
implementation.
That's why we need a little bit more
migration.
But let's take a look in practice. How
to switch from
let's call it legacy subcontracting to
the
just subcontracting subcontracting app.
All right. Contoso Italy. Where do I
start?
I will navigate to manufacturing setup.
And you will see something which is only
visible in Italy.
So, this is a old field coming from the
legacy subcontracting
and indicator that legacy subcontracting
is on. Interesting part, if you activate
the new environment, if you provision
the new environment, this toggle will be
off by default and the new
subcontracting app is installed.
But you are
until you started to use a new app
or maybe even after you started the new
app, you can disable it. You need just
to uninstall the subcontracting
and go here and choose legacy
subcontracting.
And you'll see the action. We will look
at it a little bit later.
But if you migrated, upgraded, uh
legacy subcontracting will be on, new
app is not installed, and you are
thinking about starting on how to
migrate.
So, there is a new actions.
Legacy subcontracting.
We can disable it. But before, we can do
pre-check. You can ignore it, but the
same checks will be run it anyway.
As I mentioned before, we have a
differences on how work in progress
items are implemented. That's why we are
asking you
to make sure that there is no open
transfer orders with the VIP items and
purchase orders with the VIP items.
Let's go and fix this specific problem.
Subcontracting transfer.
Here it is.
So, I have it here. What does it mean? I
can just go and post it.
I post ship.
I post receipt.
And that should be enough. All right.
The second one, it has no work in
progress lines, so that's why I can just
leave it as is, even if it is
subcontracting order.
All right. Let's continue. Actions,
subcontracting, pre-check. Now it will
be telling me about purchase orders.
Fair enough.
Subcontracting orders. And this is my
first subcontracting order.
I'll scroll.
Uh here I don't plan to uh post it. I
will I will delete it.
I'm not saying that you need to follow
this path, but you decide
how to manage your data. Maybe you
complete the documents, maybe you just
restart them, maybe cancel the
subcontracting order completely and
recreate it later once you migrated.
But I will be just deleting line four
for this demo.
All right. Now I have two subcontracting
orders. Only one had
work in progress line.
Good.
So the data is fixed. Before we jumping
there, let's uh
check one more thing.
Vendors.
I navigate to vendors
and explore
subcontracting specific field. Yeah,
subcontractor true, subcontracting
location code. So these are local
Italian fields and we plan to migrate
them.
Also we need to take a look at the
subcontracting prices.
And we can see that some prices are
defined here for this vendor.
All right. Let's close. So now by now we
already explored all the data which is
already present. So it is a vendor,
prices,
purchase and transfer orders,
and apparently production orders, but
it's a it's a given. So now the next
step
precheck.
You need to install subcontracting app.
Yeah, without it you have nothing to
migrate to. You can install it right
from here. I will choose yes.
Continue and install.
And it suggest me to run the assisted
setup. I will skip it for now because
it's
reviewed in a different session.
All right. Once app is installed, we get
back to a role center.
Uh that's how installation process
works. So to continue we need to
navigate back to manufacturing setup.
Manufacturing
setup.
Yeah, of course you can do the
preparation work up front and install
subcontracting app early.
And now let's try to disable legacy
subcontracting. Still not still not.
Here we run the check and analyze if
migration is needed. If you do not have
open documents, prices, vendors, etc. So
basically if you're not using the legacy
subcontracting at all, we based on the
data,
uh system even do not ask you to install
migration because there is nothing to
migrate. Yes, you just getting the the
new app.
So this is not a problem. But uh
otherwise,
you need to install the app and the path
is the same. So the system allows you to
install it right from here from this
manufacturing setup. I will choose yes
and get my app installed.
Perfect. App is installed and ready to
use.
All right.
Basically we again back on the role of
center because installation of the app
is a serious process.
We go to the manufacturing setup for the
like whatever third first time.
And again, yeah, you could install them
up front and have them available. So
installing app does nothing. You are in
control when exactly you want to
migrate. So you can pre-install these
apps
and wait and work on your work in
progress
documents like production orders,
purchase documents,
transfer documents to make sure that
they are uh
cleaned up
and ready. And as soon as they're ready,
then you navigate to actions, legacy
subcontracting, and finally disable
legacy subcontracting. Yes.
Data was migrated and again everything
restarted. The reason is we are
reactivating activating some application
areas. All Italian subcontracting the
legacy subcontracting is tagged with
application area. Let's find it.
Legacy subcontracting and you can it is
off.
New app is marked with
subcontracting tag, and now it's on. So,
activating this toggle is actually
changing this setting as well. But, it
is also
uh
guarded, and it controls if you have
data or not. If you have data in your
legacy subcontracting system, system
will not allow you to activate the
toggle without migration. And as soon
you
as soon as you run migration, system
does this change, and now you do
[snorts] not see legacy subcontracting
fields.
You can see the only new subcontracting
fields coming from the app, but not the
previous ones.
You also do not see subcontracting
orders.
Yeah?
Or subcontracting transfer orders, which
is basically the same. So, these
dedicated pages are not available
anymore. But, where are my purchase and
transfer orders?
Purchase
purchase orders.
They are in the same list.
You can see as normal
purchase orders. But, can I look only on
subcontracting ones? Yes, we have a view
for this one.
I got only subcontracting orders. So,
the same story goes for transfer orders.
View to subcontractor
I have something from subcontractor
I have nothing, but that's uh it's
expected. So, you can still get your
documents filtered as needed.
All right. Next one, what do we want to
look at?
We want to look at our vendors.
The subcontracting location was moved.
The link to work center is still still
here. What about prices?
Prices look absolutely the same, but
they are actually in the new table in
the in the migrated table.
What we learned?
Previously, when we just released it, we
make sure that migration is not
possible
to run in the production environment.
So, we want to
get some feedback. And thank you very
much for customers and partners in Italy
who provided us feedback. We did a lot
of improvements on the migration
process.
Appreciate it very much.
Couple of requirements, just to remind
you. Both subcontracting up and Italian
subcontracting migration up are new.
Subcontracting up you can install
different ways from AppSource or from a
inside product. Italian subcontracting
migration up is not listed on AppSource.
It's only available
to install from the tenant itself. So,
you need to open manufacturing setup and
you trigger installation. Again, if
needed, system will identify if it's
needed or not and uh
propose you to install it.
WIP
work in progress items,
purchase and transfers are
something you need to handle up front.
Otherwise, uh
migration just works. What gets
migrated?
Vendor, purchase headers, lines,
transfers, components, routing, and
subcontracting prices.
Uh minor fields are here and there.
So, that's uh basically it. Uh
Feel free to try it at any point of
time. You can create a clone of your uh
environment, install apps,
and run the migration in each company
individually
at uh point of time when it is most
convenient for you.
Thank you and ciao.